Joseph Earl

T: 07792444822

E: hello@josephearl.co.uk

LinkedIn: uk.linkedin.com/in/josephwearl

GitHub: github.com/josephearl

Values

Through 12 years of professional experience in software delivery and leadership roles, I have found that good software is delivered through close customer collaboration and a happy workforce. Guided by the Lean and Agile philosophies, I continuously seek opportunities to learn and improve. My commitment to continuous improvement and respect for people fosters an environment that fuels innovation, collaboration, and growth. I firmly believe that empathy towards customers is essential for all team members, as is the ability to respond quickly to their demands through practices like DevOps and continuous deployment.

Experience

2022-2023 Principal Technical Consultant @Waracle

Strategy and innovation for some of the UK's most pioneering clean tech startups and largest financial services and energy providers.

Responsible for: Helping to grow account relationships, developing the brand as a leader in thought leadership, leading consulting engagements, supporting sales & pre-sales.

2016-2022 Lead Technical Consultant @Thoughtworks

Large scale technology modernisation, capability development and digital product development for some of UK's leading groceries, mobility, legal and business solutions brands.

Responsible for: Leading teams, performance reviews and coaching, technical architecture and stack, operations. Hands-on.

2015-2016 Chief Technology Officer @Lenio

Keeping the spirit of giving spare change to charities alive in a digital and cashless society by automatically rounding-up purchases through banking integrations.

Responsible for: Hiring and managing technology staff, delivering investment prototypes. Hands-on.

2012-2015 Head of Mobile @Powa Technologies

Delivering innovative omni-channel retail experiences and mobile payment solutions for customers and businesses.

Responsible for: Hiring and managing multiple mobile teams, providing mobile development, testing and release capabilities across iOS & Android. Hands-on.

2011-2012 Android Developer @BirdGuides

Building the next generation of apps for bird watchers.

Responsible for: Developing & releasing Android apps. Hands-on.

Skills

Management & Leadership	Practices & Techniques	Technology
People first	Customer focused	Generalist
121s	Product engineering	Java, TypeScript, C#, Kotlin,
Coaching & mentoring	Customer support	Swift, Scala, Bash, Willing to
Wellbeing & culture	Incidents, On call	learn
Performance reviews	Analytics, Metrics, KPIs	
Interviews		Full stack
DevEx	Shifting left	Backend, Spring, Quarkus,
	TDD, TBD, Pair	Express, ASP.NET Core
Lean management	programming	Responsive Web, React,
OKRs	DevSecOps, FinOps	Next.js, HTML5
Engineering management	Separation of deployment &	Mobile, iOS, Android
Lean product management	release, Feature toggles	
Team modelling & financial	Testing in production	Evolutionary architecture
forecasting		DDD, Micro services, Micro
Job requirements	Continuous delivery	Frontends, Mobile Micro
	CI/CD	Features, Serverless,
Technical leadership	Continuous deployments	Messaging, Stream
Technical strategy	Infrastructure as code	processing
Solution selection	Compliance as code	ADRs
Presentations	GitOps	
		Cloud platforms
	Agile	AWS, Kubernetes,
	Inception, Discovery,	OpenShift, Docker, Lambda
	Planning, Retrospectives,	
	Standups	Operations
	Event storming	Production deployments
	Lightweight threat	Monitoring & alerting
	modelling	Blameless post-mortems
		Operational excellence

Books that have influenced my thinking

Managing for Happiness, Leaders Eat Last, Superteams, Lean Enterprise, Accelerate, Project to Product, Team Topologies, The Phoenix Project, The Goal, QED

Education

2006-2010 2:1 MSci Theoretical Physics @Imperial College London Studying the universe and gravity with computational methods.

References available upon request